gramophone.co.uk 2012-12-30

# Haymarket Media Group Privacy Notice | gramophone.co.uk

**_1\. Introduction_**

Your personal information is being processed by Haymarket Media Group ('Haymarket'). For a full list of our brands and business divisions please visit our [web site](http://www.haymarket.com/brands.aspx). Haymarket respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal information. We comply with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998 and aim to maintain consistently high levels of best practice in our processing of your personal information. This Privacy Notice relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us through the Haymarket network of websites and/or other services provided by Haymarket.

In order to provide you with the full range of services, we may request and/or record information about you. This privacy notice explains the following:

  * the type of information we collect;
  * how the information is used;
  * when we may contact you;
  * whether we will disclose your details to anyone else; and
  * the use of cookies.

Many Haymarket websites contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy notices and we encourage you to review them. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

**_2\. What type of personal information is collected?_**

When you sign up to participate in or receive a service from any Haymarket website, such as a newsletter, competition, forum we will ask for limited personal information. We will also collect personal information from you when you subscribe to one of our magazines and when you communicate with us over the telephone or via written correspondence. This can include information such as your name, postal address, telephone or mobile number, fax number, email address, gender or date of birth. Different Haymarket websites may ask for different pieces of personal information. By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable Haymarket and its service providers to provide you with the services you select.

**_3\. How will the information be used?_**

Haymarket will use your personal information for a number of non-marketing purposes including the following:

  1. we may contact you for service related reasons that you have subscribed to, signed up for, or participate in (e.g. to make you aware of any delays in your subscription arriving on time, reminding you of a password or username, or about a comment you have made on a website.);
  2. to invite you to share your opinions and comments through a research study about the level of service you receive from us;
  3. to track traffic flows and to make our websites easier for you to use;
  4. to fulfil subscription orders;
  5. to provide a user online community; and for
  6. planning and managing our business activities by understanding aggregated analysis on behaviour and habits;

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group which includes our subsidiaries as defined in section 1159 of the Companies Act 2006

**_4\. Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?_**

Yes. Haymarket may use the information you have provided to promote the products and services of Haymarket or others.

However, be assured that we understand the irritations of unsolicited communications and are fully committed to ensuring the rights and obligations set out in the Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 are respected.

**If you don’t want it, you won’t get it**.  Any marketing communication you receive will always include a clear, simple option to refuse, or ‘opt-out’ of such future communications. You may also opt-out at ANY time by contacting us (see below).

The Telephone Preference Service (TPS) and the Mailing Preference Service (MPS) offer consumers important statutory and non-statutory protection against unsolicited marketing contact. If you are registered on either service, Haymarket will assume that your _subsequent_ submission of personal data via a Haymarket website or data capture form indicates, for the time being, your consent to receive marketing by us. **You may opt-out at ANY time by contacting us (see below).**

**_5\. Will Haymarket share my information with anyone else?_**

Haymarket may disclose your personal data where it believes it is compelled to do so by law; in particular for the prevention or detection of crime, the capture or prosecution of offenders; and the assessment or collection of tax or duty.

Occasionally, we may share your contact information with carefully selected third party companies whose products and services we feel may be of interest to you. We will keep these offers relevant to your interests. It's easy to unsubscribe from any email or mobile messages you no longer want. (see below).

We use a number of third party organisations to help provide a professional service to our customers (i.e. fulfilment bureaus, call centres, and website designers). These organizations act as data processors and are strictly controlled in how they may/may not use your personal data. We remain responsible for the protection of your data.  
Please note that some of our partners may be located outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Countries outside the EEA may not be required to protect personal information as stringently as countries inside.

**_6\. Can I find out what personal information Haymarket holds on me?_**

Under the Data Protection Act 1998 you have the right to request a copy of the personal information that Haymarket holds about you. There will be an administration fee of £10 associated with this request and will require two pieces of identification to prove your identity. Please make a written application to the Data Protection Officer, Haymarket Media Group, Teddington, Middlesex, TW11 9BE.

If any of the personal information that we hold about you is incorrect, you can click on the contact us link on each website. If the incorrect information relates to your magazine subscription, then you can contact the customers services team on 08456 777 800 who will update your details as soon as practically possible.

**_7\. Changes to the Haymarket Privacy Policy?_**

This privacy policy may be updated at any time with or without notice in order to comply with new practices or regulations. You may wish to visit this page every time you submit personal information to one of Haymarket’s websites.

**_8\. Cookies and your privacy_**

In order to enable us to provide you with a personalised browsing experience, this website uses 'cookie' information collection technology. "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are issued to your computer when you enter a website. Cookies are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive, and they can be used for a wide range of purposes, such as identifying your computer's previous visits to a website, and to ascertain the most popular features of a website.

This website uses cookies as they enable us to identify your computer when you visit the website. For example, cookies can make it possible for us to identify and automatically log in registered users of certain services on the website without the need for us to ask users for their registration details and password each time they visit. We also use cookies to develop a clearer picture of which parts of the website are the most popular to its visitors, and your preferences. Cookies are also used in behavioural advertising to identify users who share a particular interest so that they can be served more relevant adverts.

If you wish to know more about cookies and how companies like Haymarket use them, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). Information on these websites will assist you in exercising your privacy rights providing guidance on how to opt-out of future access or continued storage of information via cookies.

Following recent revisions of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 relating to the notification and use of cookies Haymarket is currently working towards implementing the new requirements in line with guidance provided by The Information Commissioner’s Office.

**_9\. Contacting Haymarket about this Privacy Policy_**

If you have any further questions or comments concerning your privacy, please contact;

MAIL:  
Data Protection Officer  
Haymarket Media Group  
Teddington Studios  
Teddington  
Middlesex  
TW11 9BE

If you don’t want to receive any more direct marketing messages then please [click here](http://www.pages05.net/haymarketmediagroupuk/optout/contact_details/).
